It's so weird. How did Joey end up kissing Charlie last night?
真是太奇怪了 乔伊昨晚最后怎么会去亲查莉呢？
- I thought you'd end up kissing Charlie. - I thought I'd end up kissing Charlie too.
-我还以为最后会是你去亲查莉 -我也这么以为啊
But surprise!
但是…惊喜！
I missed most of the party.
我错过大部分的派对
Charlie's a girl, right?
查莉是女生，对吧？
Yeah, she's this new professor in my department that I did not kiss.
是的，她是刚到系上来 而我没亲到的那个新教授
I don't know why Joey had to kiss her. Of all the girls at the party, God!
我不知道为什么乔伊要亲她 有这么多女生在派对上，天啊！
- Why do you care so much? - Yes, Rachel. Why do you care so much?
-你为什么这么在乎呢？ -是啊，瑞秋，你为什么这么在乎呢？
Because Ross is the father of my child.
因为罗斯是我孩子的父亲
You know, and I want him to hook up with lots of women.
你知道的，而我希望他可以有机会 跟很多女人交往
All I'm saying is, I don't think that Joey and Charlie have anything in common.
我的意思是说，我不认为乔伊跟查莉 有任何相同之处
I don't know. They seemed to have a shared interest in each other's tonsils.
我不知道，他们似乎对彼此的扁桃腺 有相同的兴趣
Wow. Joey and a professor. Can you imagine if they had kids?
哇，乔伊跟大学教授 你们能想像万一他们有小孩吗？
And if the kids got her intelligence..
如果小孩子遗传到她的智慧…
and Joey's raw sexual magnetism..
还有乔伊的原始性吸引力…
those nerds would get laid!
书呆子还可以随时来一跑！
All right. So, Ross, you're okay with all this? I mean..
好了，罗斯你对这一切都没关系吗？ 我是说…
It's no big deal. I just met her. I'm fine with it.
又没有什么大不了的，我才刚认识她 我没事的
God, I forgot how hot she was.
天啊，我忘了她有多辣了
I'm gonna get some more coffee.
我要去多倒些咖啡
- Oh, you know, I'll come with you. - Okay.
-喔，我跟你去 -好的
- So a professor, huh? - Yeah. She is cool. And she's so smart.
-是教授吗？ -是啊，她真酷，而且很聪明
Her mind is totally acrimonious.
她的内心是完全的“尖酸刻薄”
Guess that's not how she used it.
她好像不是那样用那个字的
I feel like I owe you an explanation.
我觉得我应该向你解释…
I don't ordinarily go around kissing guys at parties.
我通常不会在派对上乱亲男生的
I'm..
我…
Well, I'm kind of embarrassed. I really hope you don't think less of me.
嗯，我有点难为情 我希望你不会因此而瞧不起我
Think less of you? No. I don't think less of you.
瞧不起你？我不会瞧不起你的
I mean, you saw someone you liked and you kissed them.
我是说，你看到喜欢的人 然后你亲了他
Those people who like someone and don't kiss them..
那些有喜欢的人 却又不亲他们的人…
those people are stupid. I hate those people.
那些人是笨蛋，我恨死那些人了
Actually, I'm a little surprised at myself.
事实上，我自己也是很惊讶
I mean, Joey's so different from the guys I usually date.
我是说，乔伊跟我以前 交往的人太不同了
They're all professors, intellectuals. Paleontologists mostly.
他们全都是教授、高知识份子 大部分是古生物学家
- You know, very cerebral.. - Yeah, I know the type.
-你知道的，非常有理智… -是的，我知道那一类型的人
If we want to grab a bite before work, we'd better get acrimonious.
如果你想要在上班前先吃点东西 我们最好赶快尖酸刻薄
No? Am I getting close?
不对吗？意思很接近吧？
The One With The Fertility Test
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
- Hey! - Hi.
-嘿！ -嗨
Hey, you guys. Look what I just got.
嘿，你们瞧瞧我买了什么
Oh, wow! I love those! Where did you get them?
哇！我喜欢这双鞋！ 你去哪买的？
I bought them off eBay. They used to belong to the late Shania Twain.
我从拍卖网站上买的 这本来属于已过世的顺子的
Phoebe, Shania Twain is still alive.
菲比，顺子还活着
Oh, then I overpaid.
喔，那我被坑了
Hey, what's this?
嘿，这是什么？
Oh, it's a gift certificate to this new spa in SoHo.
喔，那是苏活区一间 新开水疗中心的礼券
You can't show Phoebe this. She hates those corporate massage chains.
你不能给菲比看到 她痛恨这些大型连锁按摩中心的
What, now I can't get a massage?
什么？我连按摩都不行吗？
There are so many things that she disapproves of.
有很多事情她都不准我们做
I can't eat veal. I can't wear fur.
我不能吃犊牛肉，我不能穿皮草
I can't go hunting.
我不能去打猎
- Do you want to go hunting? - I would like to have the option.
-你想要去打猎吗？ -至少我要有选择的权利
What's that? Hey, Rachel?
那是什么？嘿，瑞秋？
No, you can't go there!
不，你不能去！
You know how I feel about these big massage places.
你知道我对这些按摩中心的观感
They're putting people like me out of business.
它们害得像我这样的人失业
She wants to go hunting too!
她也想去打猎喔！
Phoebe, come on, I don't want to waste it.
菲比，别这样，我不想浪费掉它
It would be like throwing away 100 bucks.
这就好像是白白丢掉一百块
Okay, this is not about the money. Okay?
这跟钱无关，好吗？？
It's about corporate greed destroying our hearts..
这跟大企业贪婪毁灭我们的心灵…
and leaving us hollow shells.
然后让我们只剩下 空空的躯体有关
I don't care about any of that.
我根本不在乎那些
Well, do you care about friendship? I feel really strongly about this.
那你在乎我们的友谊吗？ 我对这个真的很反感
Please don't use this gift certificate. I'm asking you as a friend.
请不要用这张礼券 我以朋友的身分要求你
Oh, not as a friend. Phoebe!
喔，不要以朋友的身分，菲比！
Fine. I won't use it.
好啦，我不用就是了
- Promise? - I promise.
-保证吗？ -我保证
- Thank you. - Well, I am going hunting.
-谢谢 -不过我会去打猎的
Hey, honey. I missed you today.
嗨，亲爱的，我今天好想你
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah. Hey.
-喔，是吗？ -是啊
- What do you wanna do tonight? - Oh, well, maybe we could..
-你今晚想要做什么呢？ -或许我们可以…
Okay, trying to turn me on by making a mess?
好，想用把东西弄乱 来让我性奋吗？
Know your audience.
多了解一下你的对象
Besides, tomorrow we're doing those fertility tests.
况且，明天我们要做不孕症的检查
Until then, you need to keep your tadpoles in the tank.
在那之前 你得要把你的蝌蚪放在池塘里
Do we really need to take those tests?
我们一定要做那些检查吗？
I don't like the words they use, you know?
我不喜欢他们用的 那些字眼，你知道吗？
They're so clinical. This is a pee-pee, that's a hoo-hoo.
太医学化了 这是小弟弟，那是小妹妹
We've been trying to have a baby for a year.
我们为了要怀孕已经试了一年了
I think it's a good idea to find out if everything's okay.
我认为检查一切是否正常 是件好事
- Just a few routine tests. - But I don't want to do it in a cup.
-只是几样例行的检查 -但是我不想要弄在一个杯子里
- What is the big deal? - It's weird! You're in a doctor's office.
-有什么大不了的呢？ -很怪！在诊所里
It's not okay to do it in a doctor's office..
不能在诊所做…
but it is okay to do it in a parked car behind a Taco Bell?
但是在顶呱呱后面的 停车场就可以吗？
I cannot believe Ross told you that.
我不敢相信罗斯告诉了你
And in my defense, it was a Wendy's.
但是我要澄清的是 那是在温蒂汉堡
Look, I don't want to do these tests either.
听着，我也不想做那些检查
But I really do think it's a good idea.
但是我真的认为这是个好主意
I'm sure a doctor's office can't be worse..
我想在医院做总不会比…
than on a class trip to the Hershey factory.
在去巧克力工厂的 远足上做还糟糕吧？
Oh, yeah! Rachel talks too!
喔，是的！ 瑞秋也是大嘴巴！
Who says wine has to cost more than milk?
谁说酒一定要比牛奶贵呢？
- Hey! - Hi.
-嘿！ -嗨
- Come on in. How are you? - I'm good.
-请进，你好吗？ -我很好
- Can I offer you a drink? - Please.
-你要喝一杯吗？ -麻烦了
I have been crazed all day.
我整天都忙疯了
I had a meeting with the dean, my syllabus for summer school's due..
我跟系主任开了会 我暑期班的课程表又要交…
and I'm writing the foreword for a book.
然后我要帮一个朋友写新书的序
I had a pretty hectic day at work too. Today I had to open a door and go:
我今天工作也很忙 今天我要开门然后做…
So I am just so excited to be here.
所以我很兴奋能够来到这里
- I can't wait to explore the city. - If you need a tour guide..
-我等不及要发掘这个城市了 -如果你需要导游…
Oh, you mean it? That would be so fun.
你是说真的吗？一定会很好玩
Oh, yeah, definitely. Definitely. Okay. What do you want to see first?
喔，是一定的 好了，你想先去哪里呢？
We could go see the Kronos Quartet at Avery Fisher Hall.
我们可以去国家音乐厅听 克诺斯四重奏
Okay.
好的
There's a collection of Walt Whitman letters on display at the public library.
在市立图书馆有惠特曼书信的展览
I know.
我知道
- But first, I have to see the Met. - Okay, let me stop you right there.
-但是，我想先去看看大都会博物馆 -好的，让我先打断一下…
The Mets suck, okay?
大都会队逊毙了，好吗？
You wanna see the Yankees.
你会比较喜欢洋基队的
No. No, not the Mets. The Met. Singular.
不，不是大都会队 是大都会，是单数
Which one? They all suck.
那一队？反正他们 全部都很逊
The museum.
博物馆
I don't think so.
我可不认为这一队 会好到哪里去
- Hi there. - Hello. Welcome to Lavender Day Spa.
-嗨 -哈，欢迎光临薰衣草芳香疗法
How may I help you?
我能为您服务吗？
Hi. I have a massage appointment under Rachel Greene.
嗨，我是瑞秋葛林，我有预约按摩
- Okay. - And here is my gift certificate.
-好的 -这是我的礼券
- This has been torn up. - And taped back together.
-这被撕掉了 -而且被黏回去了
Okay. Well, I'll call you as soon as your massage therapist is ready.
好的，等您的按摩师准备好后 我会马上通知您的
- Okay. - Have a seat through the glass doors.
-好的 -请在玻璃门外的沙发坐一下
- Through the glass doors. - Through the glass doors.
-在玻璃门外 -在玻璃门外
All righty then.
好的
Phoebe, your next client's in the waiting room.
菲比，你的下一位客人 在候客室等着
Do we have to talk like that when they're not around?
当客人不在的时候 我们也要这样说话吗？
Oh, no. No, no.
喔，不不不…
Listen, is there someone who can fill in for me?
听着，有人可以帮我做这一个吗？
- Sorry. Everyone is booked. - That woman can't know I work here.
-对不起，大家都被预约了 -那女人不能知道我在这里工作
She's a friend of mine and I made this big stink..
她是我朋友，而我告诉她我很讨厌…
about how awful these massage chains are.
这些糟糕的按摩连锁店
- Then why do you work here? - Because it's good money.
-那你为什么要在这里工作呢？ -因为薪水很好啊！
But that doesn't change the fact..
但是那并不会改变…
that this is an evil, bloodsucking corporate machine.
这是个邪恶、吸血、大企业体的事实
Well, I think this is a great place to work.
我倒是觉得这是个不错的工作环境
Okay, are they listening?
好，他们有在听吗？
- Ross. Hey. - Hi.
-罗斯 -嗨
I need to talk to you about Charlie.
我需要跟你谈查莉的事
Oh, do you? Do you really?
喔，真的吗？ 有必要吗？
Yeah, I'm kind of having a little problem.
是啊，我有一点小问题…
Look, if you don't know what the word "acrimonious" means, just don't use it.
听着，如果你不知道“尖酸刻薄” 是什么意思，那就不要用它
Look, you know Charlie, right?
听着，你了解查莉，不是吗？
- She's cool, funny, her body is so.. - Get to the problem.
-她很酷、风趣，而且她的身材又很… -说重点
Right. She's just so much smarter than all the girls I've ever dated.
好的，她只是比我约会过的 所有女生全部加起来
Combined.
都还要聪明
You know? And I just.. I don't want her to think I'm stupid.
你知道吗？而我只是… 我不想要让她觉得我很笨
Are you wearing two belts?
你系两条皮带吗？
Hey, what do you know?
嘿，谁知道呢？
You were saying you didn't want to seem stupid.
你刚刚说你不想看起来很笨
Well, she wants to go to all these cultural places..
嗯，她想要去那些 很有文化的地方…
and I don't know how to talk about that stuff. You gotta help me out.
而我不知道要怎么谈论那些东西 你一定要帮我
I don't want to get involved in your guys' relationship.
我不想要介入你们的关系当中
Oh, dude, please. Come on, you're the smartest person I know.
老兄，拜托，别这样 你是我认识最聪明的人
And I really like this girl, okay? I don't want to lose her.
而我真的很喜欢这个女生，好吗？ 我不想要失去她
- Fine. - Thanks.
-好啦 -谢谢
Okay. Let's see.
好的，让我想想…
- Oh, you should take her to the Met. - The Mets.
-喔，你应该带她去大都会 -大都会队
No, no, no. The Met. The Metropolitan Museum of Art.
不，大都会 大都会艺术博物馆
Oh, that's what she meant.
喔，原来她指的是那个
If they're gonna shorten it, they should call it the "Muse, " you know?
如果他们要用简称，应该把它 叫做“博物”，你知道吗？
Short for "museum" and avoid all the confusion.
博物馆的简称，避免混淆
Yeah, most days the place is packed with confused, angry baseball fans.
是啊，很多时候那地方都挤满了混淆 又生气的棒球迷
Okay. All right, so I'll take her to the Met.
好的，那我带她去大都会
Yeah. Okay. There's this great rare bookstore on Madison Avenue.
对了，在麦迪逊大道上 有间很棒的书店
You know what? She loves architecture.
你知道吗？她热爱建筑
You should take a walk down Fifth to the St. Patrick's Cathedral.
你应该带她从第五大道散步 到圣派屈克教堂
And there, there's this great little pastry shop that she'd love.
在那边有间很棒的烘培坊 她一定会喜欢
Jeez. Sounds like you should be going on this date.
天啊，听起来好像 是你应该去约会才对
But I'm not.
但是我并没有
- And you know what..? - Okay, slow down.
-而你知道吗？ -好的，说慢一点
You're going way too fast. Okay? Just go back to the Met.
你说的太快了，好吗？ 先回去讲大都会
So you gotta tell me exactly what to do there.
你必须要详细告诉我在那边要做什么
When you walk into the museum, take a right, okay?
当你们进入博物馆时，先向右转…
That's the antiquities wing.
那边是古代文物厅
Ancient Egypt, Mesopotamia, up to the Byzantine Empire.
古埃及、美索不达米亚直到 拜占庭帝国
Okay. So I walk in the door and make a right.
好的，所以我进门以后 往右转…
I have a weird feeling about this place. How do I know..
我觉得这地方怪怪的，我怎么知道…
they won't secretly videotape me and put it all over the lnternet?
他们会不会偷录下来 然后放到网路上呢？
Because, honey, and I mean this in the sweetest way possible..
因为，亲爱的… 我以我能做到最甜美的方式告诉你…
nobody's gonna wanna watch that.
没有人会想要看的
Mr. Bing? Here you are.
宾先生？拿去吧
Go into that room and deposit your specimen into the container.
进去那间房间，然后把样本放入容器内
Deposit my specimen?
把样本放入？
I usually have to call a 900 number for that kind of talk.
我通常要打一些900电话 才能听到这种谈话
Thanks. Got it.
谢谢，知道了
All right. Honey, my tests are down the hall.
好了，亲爱的 我的检查在另外一边
- Are you sure you're gonna be okay? - Yeah, I guess.
-你确定你还好吗？ -是的，我想应该吧
Look, I know this is embarrassing, but nobody cares.
听着，我知道这很尴尬 但是没有人在乎啊
No one here even knows you.
在这里根本没有人认识你
Oh, my God!
喔，我的天啊！
Oh, come on!
喔，不会这么倒霉吧！
How great is this?
这是不是太棒了呢？
We're probably fertile. Let's go home.
我们或许没有不孕，我们回家吧
Why are you here?
你会什么会在这里呢？
Sid and I are trying again and we had trouble last time..
西德跟我想要再试一次 我们上一次有问题…
No, no, no. I mean, why? Why is she here?
不，我是说，为什么？ 为什么她会在这里？
Oh, someone's a little cranky today because they have to do it in a cup.
有人今天不太高兴因为他们要 弄到一个杯子里面…
Oh, they gave you the kiddie size.
喔，他们给你小朋友的杯子
What?
什么？
This was fun. But I've got an invasive vaginal exam to get to.
这真有趣，但是我有内诊要去做
I'd love to stay but I've got a hot date.
我也希望我可以留下来 但是我有个火辣的约会
Please go. Just let me know if you need a hand.
请便，让我知道一下如果你需要帮手
I think it just fell off.
我想它刚刚掉了
Hello, ja.
哈 是的
It's time for your massage, ja?
按摩时候到了，是的
Put your face in the hole.
把你的脸放入洞中
A Swedish massage from a real Swedish person.
真正瑞典人做的瑞典式按摩
Okay, then I'm Swedish.
好的，那我就是瑞典人
So, what's your name?
你叫什么名字呢？
It's a normal Swedish name.
只是平凡一般的瑞典名字
Ikea.
宜家
- Wow. What an interesting name. - Yeah.
-哇，真是有趣的名字 -是啊
- You know, I.. - Time for your scalp massage.
-你知道，我… -头皮按摩时间到了
Wow. I really love your..
哇，我真的好喜欢你的…
- Is something wrong? - No, it's just..
-有什么不对吗？ -不，只是…
It just feels so good..
只是觉得很舒服…
Ikea.
宜家
Hey, say, you'll know this. What's the capital of Sweden?
嘿，看你知不知道这个 瑞典的首都是哪里呢？
Stockholm.
斯德哥尔摩
Damn. I wish I knew if that was right.
该死的，希望我知道那是对还是错
Note the painterly lines and subtle impasto on this canvas.
看那些线条，潜藏多层颜料 厚涂在画布上…
Monet painted quickly, and usually outdoors..
莫内快速地作画，而且通常是在户外…
as his elusive subject was light itself.
因为他和光线一样喜欢孤独
Now, do you have any idea what you just said?
你知道你刚刚说的是什么意思吗？
No, no. My mouth says the words, my brain is thinking "monster trucks."
不，我的嘴巴说着那些字 但是我的头脑想的是“怪兽卡车”
Now, remember, when you get to the museum..
现在，记住，当你进入博物馆时…
Monet is not spelled M-O-N-A-Y. I just..
莫内的写法不是“内” 我只是…
- I wrote that out phonetically for you. - Phonetically?
-帮你用注音写下来 -注音？
Yeah, that means.. We just don't have time for this.
是的，那是… 我们没有时间讨论那些了
I gotta say, I'm really impressed you were able to memorize all this so quickly.
我得说我真的很惊讶 你可以这么快速背下这些东西
I'm an actor. I can memorize anything.
我是演员，我可以背下任何东西的
Last week on Days, I had to say:
上星期在《我们的日子》剧中 我得说：
"Frontal temporal zygomatic craniotomy."
“前端颞颧骨切开术”
- Wow. What does that mean? - No idea.
-哇，那是什么意思呢？ -不知道
But the guy I said it to dies in the next scene..
但是那个被我那样说的男的 在下一集就死了
so I guess it means, "You'll get eaten by a bear."
所以我想那可能是说 “你会被熊给吃了”
Okay.
好的
- So let's move on to the Renaissance. - Okay.
-那我们来看文艺复兴时期 -好的
Caravaggio uses chiaroscuro here..
卡拉瓦乔在这里使用了 明暗对照法…
to highlight the anguish of the central figure.
突显出中央人物的极度痛苦
Touch it. It's really bumpy.
碰触它，还真是凹凸不平
No, no, no. No ad-libbing. And, dude, you can't touch the paintings.
不，不能即兴演出 还有，你不能乱碰这些画作的
- Come on. - No. No!
-担心什么？ -不，不！
My specimen's in the room.
我的样本在房间里了
I just want to thank whoever knocked on the door while I was in there.
我只想谢谢刚刚那个 我在里面的时候敲门的人…
Really helped speed the process along.
真的帮助加速了整个流程
Janice, you're not gone?
珍妮丝，你还没有消失啊？
Sid is still in his room.
西德还在他的房间里
I don't allow porn at home, so this is like a vacation for him.
我不许家里有色情书刊 所以这对他而言简直是快乐假期
So did you do it? Did you make your deposit?
所以你做了吗？ 完成你的样品存放手续了吗？
- Yeah. The hard part's over. - That's not the hard part, honey.
-是啊，最困难的部份结束了 -那不是最困难的，亲爱的
No, there's talking to you, but Monica's coming out.
没错啊，跟你说完了 摩妮卡出来了
And we're gonna go soon.
我们很快就要走了
Chandler.
钱德
The hard part's what comes next. Aren't you worried about the results?
接下来才是最困难的部份 你难道不担心结果吗？
I mean, oh, when Sid and I did this last time, my God, I was a mess.
我是说，当西德跟我上次来做的时候 我的天，我紧张死了
I haven't even thought about the results.
我根本没有想过结果
I just assumed everything would be okay.
我只是以为一切都会没事
Well, you know what? It probably is.
结果你知道吗？或许就是没事
But what if it's not okay?
但是要是有事呢？
I mean, what if there's a reason we can't have a baby?
我是说万一我们不孕是有原因的呢？
Chandler. Look, you and Monica are meant to have children.
钱德，听着，你跟摩妮卡一定会有小孩
I'm sure it's gonna be just fine.
我敢说一切一定都没事的
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Thanks. I can't believe I didn't even think of that.
是啊，是啊，好了，谢谢 我不敢相信我竟然没有想过
I guess I was so worried about having to come here and do that.
我是说我好担心要过来这里做检验
You can do it in a Taco Bell parking lot..
你可以在顶呱呱的停车场做…
but you can't do it at a doctor's office?
但是你没有办法在诊所做吗？
It was a Wendy's!
是温蒂！
And that's the Swedish national anthem. Thank you for asking.
这就是瑞典国歌，谢谢你问了
Wow, Ikea.
哇，宜家家居
What a rich culture.
真是丰富的文化
You know what? I have a friend who's a masseuse.
你知道吗？我有个朋友也是按摩师
- Oh? Ja, ja? - Ja. She's not very good, though.
-喔？是吗？ -是啊，不过她不是很行
- And why do you think that is? - I don't know.
-你为什么会那样觉得呢？ -我不知道
Maybe it's because she's got such callousy fingers..
或许是因为她的手指很僵硬
from playing crummy guitar.
大概是弹烂吉他而来的
Or maybe she has trouble loosening your knots..
或许因为她很难放松你的筋骨
because you're such a high-maintenance tight-ass.
因为你真是个难搞的俏屁股
- Phoebe! - You know it's me?
-菲比！ -你知道是我？
Well, for like a half an hour!
嗯，知道半个小时了！
Man, you can lie about Sweden!
天啊，你还真能扯瑞典的事！
How can you come here?
你怎么能够到这里来呢？
- Why didn't you tell me you work here? - I don't have to tell you everything!
-你为什么没说你在这里工作呢？ -我不需要告诉你每件事！
You do if you're gonna make me feel guilty for getting a free massage.
如果你让我觉得来这里享受免费按摩 是很罪恶的事，那你就要
Tip's not included.
小费还是要照算的
Why did you lie to me about working here?
为什么你不敢说你在这里工作呢？
Because I was ashamed, okay? I sold out for the cash.
因为我觉得很丢脸，好吗？ 我为五斗米而折腰
And they give me benefits, like medical and dental and a four-oh-wunk.
他们提供一些福利，像是健保什么的
But, you know, you pay a price. Now I'm this corporate stooge..
但是你知道的，要付出代价的 现在我成了大公司的傀儡
and punching a clock..
每天打卡上班
and paying taxes!
然后还要缴税！
Phoebe, honey, if you hate it so much..
菲比，亲爱的，如果 你这样痛恨这工作…
you should walk out there right now and quit.
你应该马上走出去然后辞职
Be true to what you believe in.
相信你所坚信的理念
Honey, you have principles, and I so admire that.
亲爱的，你是有原则的人 所以我很钦佩你的
I don't have any.
我才是没有原则
You know what? You're right. I am gonna quit.
你知道吗？你说的对，我要去辞职
- It's time I took my life back. - Good for you, Phoebe.
-该是我重新生活的时候了 -很好，菲比
If you guys have microphones in there too, I didn't mean any of that.
如果你们在里面也有装麦克风 我在里面说的都不是真的
I love you.
我爱你们
Got you! Die! Die! Die!
打到了！死吧！死吧！死吧！
Respectfully, Professor R. Geller.
诚挚地，盖勒教授敬上
- Hey. - Hi.
-嘿 -嗨
Hey, how was the Met?
嘿，大都会好玩吗？
The museum was amazing.
博物馆真的很惊人
Yeah, Joey really knows his art, huh?
是啊，乔伊真的很懂艺术不是吗？
Not so much, no.
并不尽然，不
He had clearly memorized all this stuff to say..
很明显地他清楚地背下了要说的东西…
and some of it didn't even make any sense.
但是很多东西都很不对劲
- What do you mean? - Well, for one..
-你是什么意思呢？ -嗯，例如…
he was talking about paintings that were nowhere around.
他谈论的都是根本不在展出的绘画
Wait a minute. When you guys walked into the Met, did you go to the right?
等等，你们进入博物馆之后 是往右边走吗？
- No. No, we went to the left. - Oh, Joey, Joey, Joey.
-不不，我们往左边走 -喔，乔伊，乔伊，乔伊
Still, it seems like you guys are having a great time together.
可是你们看起来也是度过快乐的时光啊
Yeah. Yeah, it's fun.
是啊，是很好玩
What?
怎样？
Actually, Joey's your friend..
事实上，乔伊是你的朋友…
and you don't know me that well. It'd be weird.
而你也不是很了解我 这会很奇怪的
Well, I mean, a little. But no, what? Go on.
嗯，可能会有点，但是不会啦 怎样呢？跟我说
Well..
嗯…
I'm thinking that maybe Joey isn't the right guy for me right now.
我在想或许乔伊不是很适合我
You know, maybe I should be with someone..
你知道的，或许我应该跟…
I have more in common with. You know what I mean?
跟我比较相像的人在一起 你知道我的意思吗？
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah, but you know what?
是啊，但是你知道吗？
I think you should give Joey a chance.
我想你应该给乔伊一个机会
I mean, he's a great guy.
我是说他是个好男人
And sure, he doesn't know that much about art..
当然他是不知道很多艺术的东西
but you can always talk about that with someone else.
但是你可以跟其他知道的人谈论啊
- I guess that's true. - If you think about it..
-我想也是 -如果你仔细想想…
he memorized all that stuff because he thought it was important to you.
他背下所有的东西只是因为 他认为那些东西对你很重要
You know, that's the kind of guy Joey is.
你知道的，乔伊就是那样子的人
He is very sweet.
他是非常贴心的
Plus, he is hot!
还有，他真是帅毙了！
That was gonna be my next argument.
这就是我下一个要争论的
- You ready? - Yeah. Let's go.
-你准备好了吗？ -好了，我们走吧
Wow!
哇！
- Thanks, Ross. - Yeah.
-谢了，罗斯 -不客气
Hey, Ross. That art stuff worked. You hooked me up.
嘿，罗斯，艺术那些东西真是有效 你真帮了大忙
Glad I could help, man.
很高兴能够帮上忙，兄弟
Some of the stuff wasn't where you said it would be, but I made it work.
有些你说的东西并没有在那里 但是我都搞定了
It is not okay that I'm aroused by this now.
我现在不能因为这个而勃起了
Hello?
哈？
Oh. Hi, Dr. Connelly.
喔，嗨，唐纳利医生
No. Well, she's not here..
不，她现在不在…
but I can tell her.
但是我可以转告她
Should I be sitting down for this?
我应该先坐下来再听吗？
Well, so, what does that mean?
那，那是什么意思呢？
Okay. Okay, thank you.
好的，好的，谢谢你
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, sweetie.
嘿，亲爱的
Dr. Connelly just called.
唐纳利医生刚刚打电话来
With good news? Of course it's not good news.
有好消息吗？当然不是好消息
You said, "Dr. Connelly just called."
你是说“唐纳利医生刚刚打电话来”
If it was good, you'd have said, "Dr. Connelly just called!"
如果是好消息你会说 “唐纳利医生刚刚打电话来！”
So, what is it? Is it..?
那，是怎样呢？是不是…
Is there a problem? Is there a problem with me, or with you?
有问题吗？是我的问题还是你的呢？
Actually, it's both of us.
事实上我们两个都有问题
What?
什么？
Apparently, my sperm have low motility..
很显然地，我的精子活动力太低了
and you have an inhospitable environment.
而你有不适着床的环境
Well, what does that mean?
喔，那是什么意思呢？
It means that my guys won't get off their Barcaloungers..
意思就是说我的人根本没有办法出兵…
and you have a uterus that is prepared to kill the ones that do.
而你的子宫已准备好 要杀死入侵的小兵了
- It means.. - Wait, Chandler.
-意思是 -等等，钱德
It means that we can keep trying..
意思是我们可以继续尝试…
but there's a good chance this may never happen for us.
但是我们很有可能永远都不会怀孕
Oh, my God.
喔，我的天
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry too.
我也很抱歉
Well..
嗯…
we're gonna figure this out.
我们会想出办法的
I know.
我知道
- Good morning, Phoebe. - Good morning, receptionist.
-早安，菲比 -早安，总机小姐
Here's your schedule for the day. Your first client is in Room 1.
这是你今天的工作排程 你第一位客人在一号房
"Rachel Greene." Son of a bitch! She came back?
“瑞秋葛林”，狗娘养的！ 她又回来了？
Are you ready for your Scottish massage?
你准备好要享受苏格兰式按摩了吗？
Put your face in the hole, lassie!
把脸放到洞中间 小妞！（苏格兰叫法）